生活大爆炸
第四季第七集
No, seriously,
说真的
I think I've finally figured out my problem with women.
我终于明白为何自己找不到女人了
The capybara is the largest member of the rodent family.
水豚是啮齿类动物中为数最多的品种
What does that have to do with me and women?
这跟我与找女人有何关联
Nothing. It was a desperate attempt
没关联  我只是迫切想为
to introduce an alternate topic of conversation.
午餐会换个新话题罢了
My problem is, I don't project confidence.
我的问题在于  我没有展现出自信
So I decided the next time I meet a woman I think is attractive,
所以我决定  当我下次见到美女时
rather than holding back and being cautious,
我不会退缩和矜持
I'm going to assume the mantle of self-assurance.
我要展现我自信的一面
Oh, yeah? What's that look like?
是吗  那该是什么样子的呢
Hi.
你好啊
I'm Leonard.
我叫莱纳德
And you are beautiful.
你宛若天仙一般
You pop, sparkle and buzz electric.
青春  奔放  热力四射
I'm going to pick you up at 8:00,
我晚上8点钟去接你
show you a night you will never forget.
定会带给你一个永生难忘的夜晚
Where are we going?
我们今晚去哪儿呢
Good news.
好消息来了
I made it onto the team for the new Defense Department
我入选了国防部新组建的
laser-equipped surveillance satellite.
激光监测卫星小组
Excuse me.
打断一下
If we're changing topics, I believe I have first dibs
如果我们要转换话题  我的话题应该有优先权
with capybara, a rodent the size of a baby hippo.
水豚  一种体型与河马宝宝相仿的啮齿类动物
Congratulations, Howard.
恭喜你  霍华德
Thanks.
谢了
Listen, I have to get a security clearance,
听着  我必须得通过安全审核
so you guys might be hearing from the FBI.
所以联邦调查局的人可能会找你们问话
I don't want to speak to the FBI.
我不想跟联邦调查局的人说话
Why not?
为什么
I'm brown and I talk funny.
我是棕色人种而且口音搞笑
They're just doing a background check on me.
他们只是为了调查一下我的背景而已
It doesn't matter, they'll find a reason
这无关紧要  他们总会设法
to give me a one-way ticket back to Gandhi-ville.
把我遣返回甘地城的[印度]
By the way, when I say that, it's not offensive.
顺便说一下  话虽如此  但并无冒犯之意
Don't be ridiculous, Raj.
别傻了  拉杰
You're here legally.
你是合法居留的
Nobody cares. Do you know how long it's been
没人会在乎这个  你知道我因为
since I got through airport security
在机场安检时没出具
without being given a colonoscopy?
结肠镜检查报告而被困了多久吗
You know, I try very hard
我一直很努力地
to make our lunch hours educational and informative,
想把我们的午餐时间变得更为科学有益
but your insistence on talking about your own lives
但你们执着的讨论自己生活琐事的行为
stymies me at every turn.
每次都深深地阻挠了我
Fine, Sheldon, tell us about your giant rodents.
好吧  谢尔顿  跟我们谈你那个巨型啮齿类动物吧
No, you squandered your time with me,
不了  你浪费了我们探讨的黄金时间
and the moment has now passed.
而那个时刻已经一去不复返了
Feast on your disappointment,
尽情回味你们的失落吧
much as the capybara feasts on its own waste.
就像水豚回味自己的排泄物一样
[暮色2:新月]
Oh, Bella, don't you see?
贝拉  你难道不明白吗
Edward's only pushing you away because he loves you.
爱德华离开你只是因为他爱你
Coming.
来了
Dr. Koothrappali?
库萨帕里博士吗
I'm Special Agent Page, FBI.
我是联调局探员  蓓姬
May I come in?
我可以进来吗
I'd like to talk to you about Howard Wolowitz.
我想跟你谈谈霍华德·沃罗威茨
Oh, thank you.
哦  谢谢
All right. Well, how long have you known Mr. Wolowitz?
好吧  说说你认识沃罗威茨先生多久了
Rum cake?
朗姆酒蛋糕要吗
No, thanks.
不  谢了
Now, about Mr. Wolowitz...
关于沃罗威茨先生...
Seven years.
认识7年了
I see.
了解了
I'm in this country legally, you know.
我在这个国家是合法的  你懂的
I'm sure you are.
我也这么想
Now, to your knowledge,
据你所知
has Mr. Wolowitz ever committed a crime?
沃罗威茨先生曾经有过犯罪前科吗
Of course not.
当然没有
I'm here on an H-1B visa,
我来这用的是H-1B签证
（H-1B签证:外籍人士的短期非移民工作签证）
which means I can't be associated in any way
这也意味着我不可能跟任何形式的
with crime or criminal activity and I'm not.
犯罪活动扯上关系而且我也没有过
Good.
很好
To your knowledge, does Mr. Wolowitz
据你所知  沃罗威茨先生
have any foreign contacts?
有任何国外的联系人吗
No, just me.
没了  就只有我
Oh, there it is.
天呐  终于来了
Here comes a cavity search.
开始掏家底了
Excuse me?
你说什么
Please don't send me back to India, it's so crowded!
求你们别送我回印度去  那里太拥挤了
It's like the whole country is one endless Comic-Con,
整个国家像一场无止境的动漫大会一样
except everybody's wearing the same costume:
除了每个人穿着相同的装束
Indian Guy.
印度人装
- Dr. Koothrappali, I'm not... - I love this country!
-库萨帕里博士  我不是来...  -我爱这个国家
The-the baseball, the freedom,
这里有棒球  自由
the rampant morbid obesity!
和一大堆病态的肥胖人士
From California to the New York Island!
从加利福尼亚到纽约
I'm a real Yankee Doodle boy!
我都算是"洋基歌"的忠实粉丝
（洋基歌:独立战争时士兵的流行歌）
Dr. Koothrappali, please.
库萨帕里博士  请你...
My country 'tis of thee... ?
我的国家充满了...*
（他唱的实际是"My Country, 'Tis of Thee", 曾经的美国国歌, 拉杰成功穿越）
...liberty
...自由*
It's really great.
这真棒*
（忘词不会唱  囧）
So, when Howard said the FBI would be contacting me,
当霍华德跟我说会有联调局的人来找我时
I was expecting Mulder.
我以为我盼来的是穆德
Glad to see I got Scully.
没想到来了斯嘉丽
（穆德和斯嘉丽分别为《X档案》男女主角）
Who?
你说谁
Mulder and Scully.
穆德和斯嘉丽
X-Files.
《X档案》
"The truth is out there." never mind.
"真像就在那里"...  算了当我没说
Uh, so, what would you like to know?
你想了解点什么呢
You work with Mr. Wolowitz here at the university, correct?
你和沃罗威茨先生在大学里共事  对吧
Yes. Of course, we're in different departments.
是的  当然  是不同的部门
He's an engineer and I'm an experimental physicist.
他是个工程师  而我是实验物理学家
You know, one of those guys
就好比是那种
who examines the building blocks of creation
建筑监理师
and says, "Hello, maker of the universe.
并且总会说"你好啊  宇宙的建造者"
"I see what you did there.
"我看到了你的成果"
Good one."
"很屌哦"
Right.
好吧
Now, how would you characterize
你怎么形容你和
your relationship with Mr. Wolowitz?
沃罗威茨先生之间的关系呢
Good.
很好
It's a good relationship.
我们关系很好
Of course, most of my relationships are good.
当然了  我跟多数人的关系都很好
Probably because I exude confidence.
也许是因为我浑身流露着自信
People are drawn to that, you know?
这点很吸引人的  你懂吗
Confidence, not exuding.
我是说自信  不是流"露"
Do you know of any groups Mr. Wolowitz is a member of?
沃罗威茨先生是否有参加任何组织呢
You are beautiful, you know that?
你很美  你知道吗
You pop, sparkle and buzz electric.
你青春  奔放  热力四射
I'm going to pick you up at 8:00,
我八点钟去接你
show you a night you will never forget.
带你度过永生难忘的一晚
Sounds great.
听上去不错
Really?
真的吗
Can my six-foot-two
我可以带上我六尺二寸[约1.89米]
Navy seal husband come with us?
在海豹部队服役的丈夫吗
Is that...?
那是
Oh, my, I didn't see the ring with my glasses off, so...
天啊  我摘了眼镜没看到你的戒指
Look at that, I'm starting to exude.
瞧  这下我开始流"露"了
Want to get that?
你想去开门吗
Not particularly.
不是很想
Could you get that?
可以去开一下门吗
I suppose I could if I were asked.
要是有人求我去的话  也可以去的
Would you please get that?
可不可以请你开一下门
Of course.
当然可以
Why do you have to make things so complicated?
你干吗非要把事情弄得这么复杂呢
Dr. Cooper?
库珀博士吗
Yes.
是的
I'm Special Agent Page, FBI.
我是联邦调查局探员蓓姬
You say you're
你说你自己是
Special Agent Page, FBI.
联邦调查局探员蓓姬  空口无凭
Here's my I.D.
这是我的证件
And here is my Justice League membership card.
这是我正义联盟的会员卡
But that doesn't prove I know Batman.
但是这不能证明我认识蝙蝠侠
I just want to ask you a few questions
我只是想问你几个
about Howard Wolowitz.
关于霍华德·沃罗威茨的问题
Oh. All right.
好吧
I doubt anyone would risk
我想没人会冒着
the stiff penalties for impersonating a federal officer
假扮联邦政府探员的重罪
just to ask questions about a minor league engineer
来问几个关于一个患有强烈恋母情结
with an unresolved oedipal complex.
的小工程师的问题
Thank you.
谢谢
For the record, I truly support the FBI
老实说  我非常支持
in the mission which is expressed
联邦调查局为完成使命
through their motto...?
所立下的誓言
Fidelity, bravery, and integrity.
忠诚  勇敢  正直
Correct. Now to business.
回答正确  说正事吧
18 years ago, I sent the FBI crime lab samples
十八年前有人在我的门廊上
from a bag of excrement that had been lit on fire
点燃了一包粪便  我从中提取了样本
on my front porch...
寄给了联调局的罪案鉴证科
...for fingerprinting and DNA analysis.
为了提取指纹和化验DNA
Why haven't I heard back yet?
为什么我到现在还没收到任何回复呢
Well, the FBI crime lab does have a lot on its plate.
联邦调查局的罪案鉴证科事务繁忙
That's of little comfort to a nation
这对于一个想要把烧焦的粪便
attempting to scrape burning feces off its shoes.
从鞋上刮下来的人来说可不是个好消息
Would you mind if we talked about Mr. Wolowitz now?
你介不介意我们来谈一下沃罗威茨先生
A little, but go on.
有点介意  不过说吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Would you characterize him as responsible?
你认为他是个负责任的人吗
I'm going to answer that with a visual aid.
我来举证回答你这个问题吧
This is my nine-disc complete
这是我的《魔戒》三部曲
Lord of the Rings trilogy blu-ray set.
九张蓝光碟版的完整收藏
Mr. Wolowitz borrowed it,
沃罗威茨曾经借走过
damaged plastic retention hub number three...
结果把第三张碟的塑料壳弄坏了
...and then returned it to me, hoping I wouldn't notice.
然后就这样还给我  还指望我不会发现
Would you characterize that as responsible?
你觉得这叫做负责任吗
That's really not the sort of thing we're interested in.
我们对这类事情不感兴趣
You heard me say blu-ray, right?
你听到我说这是蓝光了吧
I did.
听到了
Very well.
很好
Would you be interested
那你想不想知道
in knowing that Mr. Wolowitz once snuck onto
沃罗威茨先生曾经偷偷登录我的
my World of Warcraft account and changed the name
魔兽争霸账号  然后把我一个八十级的
of a certain level-80 warlock from Sheldor to Smeldor?
术士名字由谢耳朵改成了没耳朵
I'm afraid not.
这个也不感兴趣
Is there anything else?
还有别的吗
"Is there anything else"?
"还有别的吗"
Where would you like to start?
你想从哪里开始说起
He refuses to pay fines
我借给他的书
when he's overdue with books I lend him.
他延期不还  还拒绝缴纳罚款
He crashed the Mars Rover
他为了泡妞
while attempting to impress a woman.
而撞毁了火星探测器
He recommended that I go see
他推荐我去看
the third Matrix movie because it was, and I quote,
黑客帝国三  因为  他的原话是
"just as good as the first one".
"这部跟第一部一样精彩"
If that's not irresponsible, I don't know what is.
我不知道还有谁比他更不负责任的了
The Mars Rover?
火星探测器
Did I say Mars Rover?
我有说火星探测器吗
You did.
说了
That was actually a poorly chosen example,
这个例子其实举得很烂
as it had nothing to do with me.
因为那跟我一点关系也没有
Yes, well, let's talk about it anyway.
没关系  我们还是来谈一下吧
I don't want to.
我不想谈
Not that my disinclination
但是我不愿意谈这件事
to discuss the topic should be interpreted as evidence of
并不能证明
Howard Wolowitz's culpability in the destruction
是霍华德·沃罗威茨损坏了
of government property worth millions of dollars.
上千万美元的政府财产
Thank you, Dr. Cooper.
谢谢你  库珀博士
I think I have all I need.
我想我已经问完了
Oh, good.
太好了
I was afraid you were going to fixate
我还怕你会
on that Mars Rover incident.
抓着火星探测器那件事不放呢
Hey, buddies.
伙计们
Guess who didn't get security clearance
猜猜谁由于没通过安全审查
to work on the giant space laser?
所以不能参与太空激光器的工作了
What happened?
怎么搞的
Apparently, the background interviews didn't go well.
显然  有人在背景调查时说我坏话了呗
You guys wouldn't know anything about that, would you?
这肯定跟你们几个没关系 对吧
Well, actually, I may have gotten
实际上  我跟那个女探员谈话的时候
a little tipsy when I talked to her.
可能有点喝醉了
And I may have hit on her a little bit.
我可能有点想要泡她的意思
I may have thrown up rum cake on her shoes.
我可能把朗姆蛋糕扔到她鞋上了
I see.
我知道了
Well, it's good to know, when I need you guys,
很好  每当我需要你们的时候
I can always count on you to step up and ruin everything.
我总能指望你们跳出来把事情搞砸的
I feel awful.
我好内疚
Ah, me, too.
我也是
To tell you the truth,
老实说  就算有人会搞砸
I thought if anyone was going to
霍华德的安全审核
screw things up for Howard, it'd be Sheldon.
我也觉得应该是谢尔顿的错
Well, your expectations have been subverted.
显然你的预期被推翻了
Aha.
啊哈
What are you doing up?
你怎么还不睡
Sleep eludes me, Leonard.
睡眠弃我而去了  莱纳德
Really?
是么
Maybe sleep has met you before.
可能你之前遇见过他  却错过了
Mockery?
这算是讽刺么
That's all you have to offer?
你就不能说些别的吗
I'm sorry. Why can't you sleep?
不好意思  你为什么睡不着
Who knows?
谁知道呢
I haven't watched any scary movies recently.
我最近又没看什么惊悚片
I'm no longer obsessing over why the predicted mass
也不再纠结为什么
of the quantum vacuum has little effect
量子真空质量的预测
on the expansion of the universe.
对宇宙膨胀作用甚微
And it's been weeks since I took that accidental sip of Red Bull.
我不小心喝了一小口红牛也是好几周前的事了
Did something happen today that's bothering you?
那今天发生了什么事让你纠结
Well, I did mention
我的确是对联调局探员
the Mars Rover incident to that FBI agent
提到了火星探测器那件事
and probably cost Howard his security clearance.
也许这害得霍华德没通过安全审核
- What? - But why should that keep me up?
-啥  -但我为什么睡不着呢
Because you feel guilty?
因为你感到愧疚么
Interesting.
有意思
So you're saying my insomnia is caused by a guilty conscience.
你是说我失眠是因为愧疚感作祟
Actually, you don't have insomnia.
其实你没有失眠
You're sleeping now.
你正在睡觉
Excuse me?
你说啥
You're having a guilt-ridden dream.
你正在一个因内疚感而生的梦境里
Do you have any evidence to support that hypothesis?
你这么说有什么证据吗
How about that Gorn sitting on the couch?
看到沙发上那个戈恩人了吗[星际迷航]
That seems fairly conclusive.
好吧  很有说服力
No, Gorn, no.
不  戈恩
That's where I sit.
那是我的位子
Thank you for agreeing to see me, Agent Page.
多谢你同意见我  蓓姬探员
Thank you for filing a complaint with my superior, Dr. Cooper.
多谢你向我上级投诉我  库珀博士
I understand you want to recant
我明白你想要撤销
your statement about Howard Wolowitz.
你对霍华德·沃罗威茨的说辞
- Yes. - Was your statement untrue?
-没错  -你的说辞是假的吗
No.
是真的
Then I'm afraid you can't withdraw it.
那我恐怕你没法撤销
I'm sorry. I don't recall you saying "No backsies."
不好意思  你可没说"不得回传"
Is there anything else?
还有其它事吗
Yes. I'd like to offer a laudatory statement
有  我想发表一番对霍华德
about Howard's many excellent qualities that I believe
许多优秀品质的赞美
will tip the scales back in his favor.
我相信这能扭转局势
"Howard Joel Wolowitz.
霍华德·约尔·沃罗威茨
"H is for honesty, of which he has much.
H代表诚实  他的确相当诚实
"O's for outstanding,
O代表杰出
"Which he is such.
他也正是如此
"W's for witty, he's quick with a joke.
W代表风趣  他的确很会讲笑话
- A's for artistic, his ability..." - I'm sorry.
-A代表艺术才华  他可以...  -我很抱歉
Dr. Cooper, this matter is already closed.
库珀博士  这没得谈了
But I still have "rd Joel Wolowitz" Left to go.
但名字的剩余部分我还没说完呢
It's closed.
这事儿已经完结了
I don't understand why you people
我真搞不懂你们这帮人
are picking on my friend, Howard,
要找我朋友霍华德的茬
when there are much more serious security threats to pursue.
这个国家还面临着其它更严重的威胁
For instance, when I first met Leonard,
比如  我最初遇到莱纳德的时候
he was on the verge of giving away
他就差点把导弹机密
rocket secrets to a North Korean spy,
透露给一个朝鲜间谍
and not one agent ever investigated that.
但却没有一个探员去调查这事
This is Leonard Hofstadter?
你是指莱纳德·霍夫斯塔德吗
No, it's a different Leonard.
不  是另一个叫莱纳德的
He's...
他...
Chinese, red hair, six fingers. Good-bye.
他是中国人  红头发  六根手指  再见
Raj.
拉杰
Have you seen Howard?
你看到霍华德了吗
I think he's eating lunch.
我想他在吃饭吧
Uh, Sheldon, I want you to meet Neil DeGrasse Tyson
谢尔顿  这位是尼尔·德格拉斯·泰森
from the Hayden Planetarium in New York.
纽约海登天文馆馆长
I'm quite familiar with Dr. Tyson.
我和泰森博士挺熟呢
He's responsible for the demotion of Pluto
都归功于他的一家之言
from planetary status.
冥王星不再是行星了
I liked Pluto.
我喜欢冥王星
Ergo I do not like you.
所以我不喜欢你
But I actually didn't demote Pluto.
其实不是我的一家之言
That was a vote of the International Astronomical Union.
而是国际天文联合会投票决定的
If "Ifs" And "Buts" Were candy and nuts,
要是总拿"如果"和"但是"来糊弄我们
we'd all have a merry Christmas.
圣诞节可不会开心的是吧
Think about that, Dr. Tyson.
好好想想吧  泰森博士
Is that the guy you were telling me about?
你和我说的就是他吗
Oh, yeah.
没错
Howard.
霍华德
The person at fault for you not getting a security clearance is me.
害你没通过安全审核的人是我
You?
是你
Yes, but before you get upset, I want you to know
对  在你发飙之前  我要告诉你
I went to the FBI and retracted my statement.
我去找了联调局的人撤回我的说辞
And they were okay with that?
他们同意了吗
No. If anything, I made it worse.
不  那啥  反而更糟了
In any case, I have been riddled with guilt,
不管怎样  我充满了罪恶感
which is causing Gorn-infested REM sleep.
搞得戈恩人都跑进了我梦里
So, I'm here now to say I'm sorry.
所以我来对你说抱歉
Are you kidding me?
你开什么玩笑
You've set my career back at least two years,
你害得我的职业发展倒退了至少两年
and you think you can make it right with "I'm sorry"?
你觉得说句抱歉就能算了吗
Yes.
是的
I followed the social protocol.
我遵循了社交礼仪
I attempted to right the wrong, and when I failed to do so,
曾努力想要纠正错误  但我失败了
I delivered a heartfelt apology.
所以我表示诚挚的抱歉
Now you say,
现在你得说
"Apology accepted,"
"我接受你的道歉"
and I will offer you a one-time-only high five.
而我和你击下掌  仅此一次
Your apology is not accepted.
我不接受你的道歉
You're tricking me.
你开玩笑吧
It really is, isn't it?
其实你接受了吧
Leave me alone, Sheldon.
别烦我  谢尔顿
Dr. Cooper, I just wanted you to know
库珀博士  我想告诉你
I'm sorry for the role I played in the Pluto matter.
我很抱歉我对冥王星的所作所为
Oh, shut up.
闭嘴
Sheldon?
谢尔顿
Hello.
你好
What are you doing here?
你怎么会在这
I have troubles, Penny.
我有麻烦了  佩妮
I've come to pour them out
我想来找充满同情心的
to the sympathetic ear of the local barkeep.
当地酒吧酒保一吐心事
You know, they have a really nice bar over at the Olive Garden.
其实橄榄园那边就有个不错的酒吧
I don't like the Olive Garden.
我不喜欢橄榄园
They treat me like family.
他们对我跟家人似的
- Okay, Sheldon. What can I get you?  - Alcohol.
-好吧谢尔顿  想喝点什么  -酒
Could you be a little more specific?
能再具体点吗
Ethyl alcohol.
乙醇
40 milliliters.
40毫升
I'm sorry, honey. I don't know milliliters.
抱歉亲爱的  我不懂毫升制
Ah. Blame President James "Jimmy" Carter.
那得怪詹姆斯·吉米·卡特总统
He started America on a path to the metric system
他让美国开始实行公制体系
but then just gave up.
却又半途而废
He wonders why he was a one-term president.
他还想不明白自己为何不能连任总统
Would you say that's about 40 milliliters?
你说这里差不多是40毫升吧
- More or less.  - Great.
-差不多  -很好
Now, where were we?
咱说到哪了
I believe you were about to ask me to choose a cocktail.
相信你马上就要让我点一种鸡尾酒了
Fortunately, thanks to computer-savvy alcoholics,
幸好  拜嗜酒的电脑通们所赐
there's an app for that.
正好有开发这应用
Let's see.
看看
Harvey Wallbanger. Eh.
哈维撞墙  算了
Sex on the Beach. I hardly think so.
海滩性爱  我可不要
Rob Roy, silk Slipper, Mad Hatter.
罗布罗伊  丝绸拖鞋  疯狂鞋匠
I'll have a Rosewater Ricky.
给我来一杯玫瑰花水里奇
- A what? - You'll need pitted,brandied cherries, gin,
-什么酒  -需用到去核酒酿的樱桃  琴酒
rosewater, Angostura Bitters and overproofed rum.
玫瑰花水  安古斯图拉苦味酒和高度朗姆酒
Now, first, dust the cherries with sugar,
首先  在樱桃上撒上糖
then spray them with a mixture of rum and bitters.
然后喷上朗姆和苦味酒
Then ignite the rum, caramel...
再点燃朗姆酒  将饴糖...
Here you go -- one Rosewater Ricky.
给你  你的玫瑰花水里奇
That's not how it looks in the picture.
跟照片上的不像
Oh, yeah, you know, every bartender makes it differently.
是啊  不过每位酒保调法都稍有差异
Why don't you give it a try.
何不试试再说
All right.
好吧
To the metric system.
敬公制体系
I can't taste the cherries.
我没尝到有樱桃味
All right. Sheldon, what's on your mind?
好吧  谢尔顿  你到底在烦恼什么
I wronged Howard, and he won't accept my apology.
我对不起霍华德  他不接受我的道歉
Oh, right, that.
哦那件事啊
Yes, Leonard told me. Sorry, honey.
莱纳德跟我说了  很遗憾亲爱的
Penny, you face failure on a daily basis.
佩妮  你每天都面对着失败
How do you cope?
你是怎么处理的
I drink.
我喝酒啊
To drinking.
敬喝酒
Nope.
不行
If only there were some way to force Howard to accept my apology
真希望有什么能强迫霍华德接受我的道歉
so I could escape this miasma of guilt.
让我逃脱这内疚的深渊
You know, sometimes stuff just happens,
有些事它注定要发生
and there's nothing you can do about it.
你是无能为力的
Lisa Peterson hasn't talked to me since the 11th grade,
比如  丽莎·皮特森从高二就不跟我讲话
because no matter how much you apologize,
因为不管怎么道歉
you can't go back and un-dry-hump someone's boyfriend.
都改变不了勾走她男友的事实
I see.
我明白了
You're saying I'm facing Starfleet Academy's
你是说我面对的是星舰学院
unwinnable command scenario: the Kobayashi Maru.
不可能完成的测试  小林丸号测验
Exactly.
没错
Sometimes you can't win.
有时候注定你赢不了
Captain Kirk won.
柯克船长就赢了
Kirk cheated.
柯克作弊了
Impressive that you know that.
真不敢相信你知道这个
It's hard to believe i'm actually having this conversation with you.
难以置信我竟然跟你在讨论这些
Right there with you.
佩妮与你同在
Kirk beat the Kobayashi Maru by reprogramming the simulator.
柯克通过改编测试程序  通过了该测试
- That's it. - What?
-就这么办  -什么
- I'll reprogram Howard. - What...?
-我要改编霍华德  -什么
Sheldon, you can't reprogram people.
谢尔顿  人是没法改编的
No, you can't reprogram people.
不  是你不能改编而已
To James Tiberius Kirk.
敬詹姆斯·T·柯克船长
Hello, all.
各位好
Howard, you're feeling better about me today, aren't you?
霍华德  今天没那么生我气了  是吗
Not really.
不是
Yes, you are.
一定是的
I'm using neurolinguistic programming
我正用神经语言学规划法
to modify your thought patterns.
修正你的思考模式
Go away, Sheldon.
滚远点  谢尔顿
There's a $9.95 e-book down the drain.
将近10美元买的那电子书就这么废掉了
What's in the bag?
那袋子里是什么
It's for Howard.
是给霍华德的
Oh. Sheldon, you can't fix this with gifts.
谢尔顿  这事不是送个礼就能算了的
Nevertheless, I've hurt you,
不管怎么说  我伤害了你
and whether you forgive me or not, I want you to have this.
不管你原不原谅我  我都要给你这个
You're giving me a couch cushion?
你送我个沙发垫
No.
不是
The cushion is merely symbolic.
垫子只是象征性的
I'm giving you my spot on the couch.
我送你的是我沙发上的专座
But you love that spot.
但你很爱那专座的
No. I love my mother.
不  我很爱我妈妈
My feelings for my spot are much greater.
而我对我专座的感情  要强烈得多
It is the singular location in space
它是宇宙中独一无二属于我的
around which revolves my entire universe.
环绕着它  是属于我的整个宇宙
And now it's yours.
现在它是你的了
Oh, my God, dude. Now you have to forgive him.
天哪兄弟  你一定要原谅他
All right.
好吧
Apology accepted.
我接受你的道歉
High five.
击掌
Not too hard.
别太用力
Thank you.
谢谢
I haven't cried like this since Toy Story 3.
自《玩具总动员3》之后  我就没这么哭过了
I got to tell you, Sheldon,
不得不承认
I understand why you chose this spot.
谢尔顿  我总算明白你为何选这个专座了
I mean, the temperature is good, but there's no draft.
温度正好  也没什么风
I can see the television, but I can still talk to...
能观赏电视  同时还能聊天...
I changed my mind. Get out of my spot.
我改主意了  滚出我的专座
How long?
多久
94 seconds.
94秒